Savannah Hammerton

PHD STUDENT, EPIDEMIOLOGY & BIOSTATISTICS

University of Georgia College of Public Health

□ 423 544 2453 | 💌 savannah.hammerton@uga.edu | 🏕 smhammerton.com | 🕡 smhammerton | 🛅 smhammerton

About

Graduate student working towards PhD in Epidemiology & Biostatistics (concentration in Data Analysis and Modeling). Particular interest and research emphasis in infectious diseases, infectious disease dynamics and modeling, and data analysis. Past experience in healthcare, providing strong contextual understanding of disease determinants, prevention, treatment, and outcomes, as well as an understanding of the real world implications of public health research and practice on individuals. This experience also drives context-aware data analytic approaches to answering epidemiological questions. Passionate and driven to build a career that benefits others.

Education

University of Georgia Athens, GA

PHD EPIDEMIOLOGY & BIOSTATISTICS (DATA ANALYSIS & MODELING EMPHASIS)

2022-Present Athens, GA

MS EPIDEMIOLOGY & BIOSTATISTICS (EPIDEMIOLOGY EMPHASIS) | CERTIFICATE IN INFECTIOUS DISEASE EPIDEMIOLOGY

7 tt 1 C 1 1 3, 0 7 t

Columbus State University

University of Georgia

Columbus, GA

BS, HEALTH SCIENCE

2018-2020

Chattanooga College Chattanooga, TN

DIPLOMA, PRACTICAL NURSING (SUMMA CUM LAUDE, DIRECTOR'S AWARD FOR CONSISTENT ACADEMIC AND CLINICAL

2014-2015

Excellence)

Relevant Experience _____

University of Georgia, Department of Epidemiology & Biostatistics

Athens, GA 2022-Present

GRADUATE RESEARCH ASSISANT

• Assist Dr. Andreas Handel in research for the Center for Influenza Vaccine Research for High-Risk Populations (CIVR-HRP) grant at the University of Georgia. Aid in research and data analysis on influenza vaccines, particularly data related to improved seasonal and universal influenza vaccine

- development.

 Perform secondary data analysis research on influenza antibodies as correlates of protection and apply protection probability curves to vaccine
- immunogenicity data to assess and compare vaccine efficacy.

 Perform secondary data analysis research on norovirus antibodies as correlates of protection to support vaccine research and development.
- Use bayesian modeling approaches to answer complex research questions with human clinical trial data.

Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, National Center on Birth Defects and Developmental Disabilities

Atlanta, GA

RESEARCH EPIDEMIOLOGIST

2022-Present

- Support the MAT-LINK (MATernaL and Infant Network to Understand Outcomes Associated with Medication for Opioid Use Disorder during Pregnancy) team as SWEP (Student Worksite Experience Program) volunteer.
- · Conduct data cleaning, analysis, and management using statistical software (e.g. SAS, R, etc.), and interpretation.
- Assist team with data quality assurance checks and other reviews of data. Conduct literature reviews related to opioid use disorder, pregnancy, infectious diseases, and other topics.
- Develop instructional material on use of R and RMarkdown for reports and publications.
- Support the development of statistical briefs, standard operating procedures, and publically available code for outcome identification using ICD-9 and ICD-10 codes.
- · Perform primary and secondary analyses for conference presentation and manuscript development.

University of Georgia, Department of Epidemiology & Biostatistics

Athens, GA

GRADUATE DEPARTMENTAL ASSISANT

2021-2022

- · Assist in administrative departmental tasks, faculty retreats/meeting planning, and department event planning.
- Create and maintain spreadsheets on department classes, students, etc.
- Develop presentation materials and assist in orientation.
- Generate documents with information on degree programs, Graduate School processes, etc.
- Participate in research with Dr. Jose Cordero, planning and implementing a systematic review of environmental exposures and preterm birth.